Guide to the Julia Driver Collection of Women in Photography
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Julia Driver collection of women in photography.
1845-1940
1855-1900
GEN MSS 690
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.63
(16 boxes)
This collection consists chiefly of 1559 photographs collected by Julie Driver that represent work by over 550 commercial women photographers, 1845-1940. The collection also includes thirty examples of cased photographs, which consist of ambrotypes and daguerreotypes, 1845-1862. The collection is rich in card photographs, especially cartes-de-visite and cabinet photographs created during the second half of the nineteenth century, as well as some other photographic print formats, items of ephemera and printed material. Nearly two-thirds of the women represented in the collection worked in the United States of America. Of the American photographers, nearly a quarter worked in Illinois or New York. Significant numbers worked in Iowa, Michigan, and Ohio. Women photographers from England and Sweden are also well-represented in the collection. Other represented nations and localities include Algeria, Austria, Belgium, Canada, Denmark, Egypt, Finland, France, Tahiti, Germany, Ireland, Japan, Malta, Norway, Scotland, Spain, Switzerland, and Wales.
Driver, Julia, 1961-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Julia Driver, 2010-2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Julia Driver (born 1961)
Julia Driver is a collector of photography. She is also a philosopher with research interests in normative ethical theory and moral psychology. Her works include Uneasy Virtue (2001) and Ethics: The Fundamentals (2005).
Scope and Contents
This collection consists chiefly of 1559 photographs collected by Julie Driver that represent work by over 550 commercial women photographers, 1845-1940. The collection also includes thirty examples of cased photographs, which consist of ambrotypes and daguerreotypes, 1845-1862. The collection is rich in card photographs, especially cartes-de-visite and cabinet photographs created during the second half of the nineteenth century, as well as some other photographic print formats, items of ephemera and printed material. Nearly two-thirds of the women represented in the collection worked in the United States of America. Of the American photographers, nearly a quarter worked in Illinois or New York. Significant numbers worked in Iowa, Michigan, and Ohio. Women photographers from England and Sweden are also well-represented in the collection. Other represented nations and localities include Algeria, Austria, Belgium, Canada, Denmark, Egypt, Finland, France, Tahiti, Germany, Ireland, Japan, Malta, Norway, Scotland, Spain, Switzerland, and Wales.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Series I. Cased Photographs, 1845-1962. Series II. Card Photographs and Other Photographic Materials, 1845-1940.
Photographers; Women photographers; Women photographers -- Miscellanea; Women photographers -- Pictorial works; Ambrotypes (photographs); Cased photographs; Daguerreotypes (photographs); Photographic prints; Studio portraits; Driver, Julia, 1961-
- Cased Photographs, 1845-1862; Series I; 2
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by the surname of the photographer or the corporate name of the studio.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of daguerreotypes and ambrotypes primarily in contemporary glass mats and decorative cases that document the work of women photographers and their partnerships. If known, each entry in this guide includes the life dates of the photographer, the locations active, work dates, and known aliases.
  - Barberon, Jean, Madame
    Biographical/Historical note
    Active in Bordeaux, France, circa 1855
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a woman, circa 1855; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 1a)
      Affixed advertising label on the verso, "Rue St. François, No. 9, Photographie Par Mr. & Mme. Barberon. Sur Plaque, Papier, Verre, Etc. Nouveaux portraits au Daguerreotype sans Miroitage pouvant se voir tous sons Pris tres moderes - Resemblance garantie. Leçon aux Amateurs"
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a woman, circa 1855; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 1b)
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a man, circa 1855; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 1c)
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a woman, 1857 Avril 9; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Ink inscription on verso: 9 avril 1857, âge de 15 ans et 34 jours, Canse? Julas
  - Chambefort, Maria, Mademoiselle (1818-1875)
    Active in Mâcon and Roanne, France, circa 1850-1875
    Also known as Mademoiselle Jeanne Marie Perraud or Madame Jean Louis Chambefort
    Each item has a labels affixed to its verso, "Portraits en Tous Genres et de toutes dimensions. Melle Maria Chambefort, Artiste Photographie. Hôtel Sauvage, Mâcon. Nouveaux procédé américains. Par ce mode d'opération, toute personne peut, en une minute de pose, avoir son portrait d'une ressemblance et d'une exécution irreproachables, pou médaillon bracelet, port-monnaie, éerin, camée, etc. On opere tous les jours et par tons les temps de 9 h. du matin á 6 h. du soir."
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat and frame of a woman and a boy, circa 1850-1852; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1A, Folder 2)
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a woman and a girl, circa 1850-1852; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a woman, circa 1850-1852; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Darré, Jean, Madame
    Both cased photographs have a label affixed to their verso, "Rue Maleret, No. 16. Jn. Darré, Peinte d'Armoiríes Pour Salons & Voitures. Mr. & Mme. Darré, Font les portraits colorés au Daguerréotype. Ressemblance garantie á des prix modérsal"
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat and frame of a woman and boy, circa 1855; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a boy, circa 1855; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1A, Folder 6)
  - Fehrenbach, Isabel Elisha, Madame (1831-1877)
    Active in London, England, 1854-1877
    Also known as Mrs. Emilian Fehrenbach
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a man, circa 1855; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Probably created by Emilian Fehrenbach (died 1867)
      Blindstamp on back of case, "E. Fehrenbach, Artist, 111 Strand"
  - Fish, Rhoda Ward, Mrs. (1816-1875)
    Active in Leicester, England, circa 1855-1865
    Also known as Mrs. R. R. Fish or Mrs. Robert Russell Fish
    - Ambrotype in a glass mat and frame of a woman and boy, circa 1855-1860; (1 quarter plate ambrotype) (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Label affixed on the verso, "Please Note the Address: Victoria Photographic Rooms, Rutland Street, Leicester. The brilliant finish given to our Portraits has much recommended them. The Photographs and Colors Warranted Not to Fade. A Superior Likeness on Tablet, --just the thing to send by Letter, from 1/. Mrs. Fish in Attendance Daily. Portraits &c. Copied in a very Superior Style; and the Size Increased or Deminished [sic]"
  - Gelot-Sandoz, Madame
    Active in Paris, France, circa 1844-1845
    - Daguerreotype not in a case of a man, circa 1844-1845; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Label affixed on the verso, "Portraits Photogéniques á l'ombre par tous les temps pas Mme. Gelot-Sandoz, Boulevart Poissonnière, 2. Paris"
    - Daguerreotype not in a case of a man, circa 1844-1845; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Paper mat on recto stamped, ""Mme. Gelot-Sandoz, Boult. Poissonnière, 2."
      Cover glass broken.
  - Isabella, Madame
    Active in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, circa 1857
    Also known as the North American Daguerreotype Galleries
    - Daguerreotype not in a case of a woman, circa 1857; (1 ninth plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Accompanied by an advertising card, "North American, Daguerreotype Galleries. S.W. Cor. Of 6th & Chestnut St., Philadelphia. Pictures taken for 25 cents and upwards, either on glass, paper, or otherwise, can be taken in Rainey [sic] or Cloudy Weather by Madam Isabella, Assited [sic] by the Best American Artists"
  - Jennie
    Active in Lebanon, Ohio, circa 1855
    - Daguerreotype in a half case of two women, circa 1855; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Etched inscription on verso of copper plate, "Taken by Jennie at L. Motes, Mulberry St., Lebanon, Ohio"
  - Jube, Mary Ann Sidell, Mrs. (1820-1881)
    Active in New York City
    Also known as Mrs. T. S. Jube or Mrs. Thomas S. Jube
    Each item has a letter-pressed strip label under cover glass, "T. S. Jube, 83 Bowery"
    - Daguerreotype in a half case of a child, a woman, and a man, circa 1856; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ambrotype in a full case of two men, circa 1859; (1 half plate ambrotype) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Ambrotype in a full case of a woman wearing eyeglasses, circa 1959; (1 sixth plate ambrotype) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Ambrotype in a half case of a boy, circa 1859; (1 sixth plate ambrotype) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - La Nina
    Active in New York, circa 1856-1858
    Each item has an impression on velvet case liner, "Taken by La Nina"
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a woman, circa 1856-1858; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a woman, circa 1856-1858; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a man, circa 1856-1858; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Leonard, A., Mrs.
    Active in the United States of America, circa 1855-1860
    Also known as Mrs. J. Leonard
    - Ambrotype in a half case of a woman and child, circa 1855-1860; (1 sixth plate ambrotype) (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Ink stamp in case, "J. Leonard's Ambrotype Car. Mrs. A. Leonard"
  - Macfarlane, Miss
    Active in Camden, [New Jersey?], circa 1855-1860
    - Ambrotype in a full case of a young man, circa 1855-1860; (1 ninth plate ambrotype) (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Accompanied by an advertising card, "Price List. Miss Macfarlane's Pictures, Taken at her Saloon, in Camden. Ambrotypes, From 25 cents up to $10. Permeotypes, From 50 cents up to $5. Mezzotypes, From 50 cents up to $15. Photographs, From $3 up to $25. Melleotypes, From 50 cents up to $15. Melainotypes, From 50 cents up to$5 00. And Warranted to Suit." The advertising card also includes a list in pencil on its verso that includes charcoal, cleag [sic] light, feniel [sic], and camp J.W., as well as numbers.
  - Reed, Candace McCormick, Mrs. (1818-1900)
    Active in Quincy, Illinois, as well as Canton, La Grange, and Palmyra, Missouri, 1848-1890
    Also known as Mrs. W. A. Reed, Mrs. Warren A. Reed, Excelsior Gallery, or Reed & Humphrey
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a woman, circa 1854-1856; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Impression on velvet case liner, "Reed & Humphrey, Artists, Whig Building, Quincy, Ill."
  - Rodanet, H., Madame
    Active in Bordeaux and Rochefort, France, circa 1855
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a young man and girl, circa 1855; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Label affixed on the verso, "Mme H. Rodanet," as well as an accompanying ink inscription, "Louis Duiguo, 17 ans Louise Duiguo, 12 ans"
    - Daguerreotype not in a case of a woman, circa 1855; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Label affixed on the verso, "Portraits au Daguerréotype, Coloriés, Fait à l'ombre et par tous les temps, Par Mad. H. Rodanet"
  - Short, Ruth, Mrs. (born circa 1821)
    Active in Cleveland, Ohio, 1851-1860
    Also known as Mrs. S. P. Short
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a man, circa 1855; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Impression on velvet case liner, "Mrs. Short, Artist"
  - Taylor, Ann, Mrs. (born circa 1806)
    Active in Glasgow, Scotland, 1857-1862
    Also known as Mrs. John Taylor
    - Ambrotype in a full case of a young woman, 1857-1862; (1 ninth plate ambrotype) (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Blindstamp on mat, "Taylor, 46 Jamaica St., Glasgow"
  - Wehnert, Bertha Beckmann, Frau (1815-1901)
    Active in Leipzig, Germany and New York City, 1843-1883
    Also known as Berthe Beckmann, Bertha Wehnert-Beckmann, or Frau Edward Wehnert
    - Daguerreotype in a glass mat of a man, identified as Caspar Hirzel-Lampe (1798-1866), Consul General of Switzerland in Leipzig., 1845-1849; (1 quarter plate daguerreotype) (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Label affixed on the verso, "Bertha Wehnert, geb. Beckmann. Daguerreotypistin in Leipzig, Burgstraase, No. 8, Firma Eduard Wehnert," as well as another affixed label with ink inscription, "Consul Hirzel in Leipzig + in Zürich"
  - White, Lydia B. Webb, Mrs. (born 1826)
    Active in Providence, Rhode Island, 1854-1860
    Also known as Mrs. Joseph White or Mrs. Granville S. Stevens
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a man, 1854-1860; (1 ninth plate daguerreotype) (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Accompanied by an advertising card, "J. White & Co.'s, 25 cent Ambrotypes and Daguerreotype, 44 Westminster St. South Side, Providence, R.I. All styles of Cases constantly on hand – sold less than half charged at other places. This establishment has the best arranged light in the State, up one flight of stairs only"
  - Wilde, Augusta, Miss (born circa 1832)
    Active in Savannah, Georgia; Baltimore, Maryland; Asheville, Charlotte, Greensboro, and Hissborough, North Carolina; and Charleston and York, South Carolina, 1849-1854
    Also known as Dr. Wilde and Daughter or Mrs. Calvin Smith Mosher
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a woman, 1849-1854; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Impression on velvet case liner, "Dr. Wilde & Daughter, Artist"
    - Daguerreotype in a full case of a man, 1849-1854; (1 sixth plate daguerreotype) (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Letter-pressed strip label under cover glass, "Dr. Wilde and Daughter, Artists"
- Card Photographs and Other Photographic Materials, 1845-1940; Series II; 5.83
  Series I is organized into three subseries: Photographic Materials; Photographic Materials by Men; and Oversize Photographic Materials
  This series consists of photographic materials, chiefly card photographs in the form of cartes-de-visite and cabinet photographs, as well as some variant styles of card photographs and other photographic print formats. There are also some scattered items of ephemera and printed material. The series documents work by over five hundred women photographers or their partnerships from the middle of the nineteenth century to the turn of the twentieth century. Only the work of Minnie F. Libby is referenced in multiple subseries.
  The subjects for the majority of images are not documented in this series. However, descriptions include names of identified individuals, as well as notes concerning unique subject matter. Subjects include wedding portraits, studio portrait that include animals, exterior views, and portraits of children dressed for baptisms and confirmations.
  - Photographic Materials
    This subseries consists of vintage photographic prints, chiefly cartes-de-visite and cabinet photographs, but also including some other card photographs, tintypes, and ephemera. Photographic materials with dimensions larger than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.) are located in the Oversize Photographic Materials subseries
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by the surname of the photographer or the corporate name of the studio.
    - Albright, Frances Emma Luse, Mrs. (circa 1850-1912), circa 1890; (1 cabinet photograph and 1 panel photograph) (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Active in Coffeyville and Kansas City, Kansas, as well as Santa Fe and Albuquerque, New Mexico, circa 1874-1912
      Also known as Mrs. John G. Albright
      Includes a portrait of Lora H. Cooper (born circa 1871) of Albuquerque, New Mexico, as well as a portrait of a woman posed standing and probably holding a high school diploma
    - Aldridge, J. E., Mrs., circa 1866; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 32)
      Active in Chicago, Illinois, circa 1866-1865
    - Allen, Eliza, Mrs. (circa 1816-1900), circa 1870; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Active in Manchester, Maidenhead, and Chelsea, England, as well as Sydney, Australia, circa 1859-circa 1880
      Also known as Mrs. William Bradley or Mrs. Oswald Allen
    - Allen, Eunice L., Mrs. (born 1843), circa 1876; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Active in Oswego, New York, circa 1876
      Also known as Mrs. M. H. Allen, Mrs. Milton H. Allen, or M. H. Allen & Lady
    - Allen, Laura T., Mrs., circa 1887-1888; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Active in San Francisco, California, 1874-1888
      Also known as Mrs. L. T. Allen, Mrs. B. G. Allen, Mrs. Bennett Graham Allen, Wing & Allen, Allen & Hay, or Allen & Company
    - Allen, Mary, Mrs., circa 1865; (4 cartes-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Active in Norwalk, Ohio, 1859-1865
      Also known as Mrs. M. Allen or Mrs. George P. Allen
      Includes a portrait of Romando Zenas Owen (born 1850) from Townsend, Ohio, as well as a portrait of man wearing a United States Army frock coat with a sergeant rank
    - Allison, Sarah C., Miss (born 1856), circa 1900; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 37)
      Active in Worthington, Indiana, circa 1900-1910
    - Andersen, Eline, circa 1900; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Active in Helsingør, Denmark, circa 1900
    - Anderson, Klara, circa 1895; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Active in Klintehamn and Visby, Sweden, circa 1895
      View of a street, probably in Visby, Sweden
    - Anderson, L. S., Mrs., circa 1866; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Active in Elgin, Illinois, circa 1864-1866
    - Anderson, Louise, circa 1880-1891; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 41)
      Active in Halmstad, Sweden, circa 1880-1891
      Also known as
    - Andersson, Selma, circa 1885; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 42)
      Active in Simrishamn, Sweden, circa 1885
    - Andruss, Dolly Bell, Mrs., circa 1866; (13 cartes-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 43)
      Active in Amboy, Illinois, circa 1860-1868
      Also known as Mrs. W. B. Andruss or Mrs. William Benajah Andruss
      Includes a portrait of Elizabeth Gardner (born circa 1832) created on March 15, 1866
    - Archer, D. J., Mrs., circa 1868; (2 cartes-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Active in Columbus, Ohio, circa 1860-1872
    - Asker, Julie, circa 1870-1880; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 45)
      Active in Örebro, Karlstad, Säffle, and Trossnas, Sweden, circa 1870-1880
    - Austin, Misses, circa 1900; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 46)
      Partnership between sisters Amy C. Austin (born circa 1877) and Mary E. Austin (born circa 1873)
      Active in Saint Albans, England, circa 1900-1914
    - Balch, Eliza Vaughan, Mrs. (circa 1798-circa 1871), circa 1860; (4 cartes-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 47)
      Active in New York City, 1854-1860
      Also known as Mrs. Aaron Leland Balch
      Includes portraits of Richard Floyd Blydenburgh (circa 1836-1866) and George De Revere (born 1825)
    - Baldwin, Lylia A., Mrs. (born circa 1821), circa 1872; (4 cartes-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 48)
      Active in New London and Wausau, Wisconsin, circa 1872
      Also known as Mrs. L. A. Baldwin
    - Barat, Margaret, Mrs. (born 1833), circa 1865; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 49)
      Active in Banbury and London, England, 1864-1877
      Also known as Mrs. G. Barat, Mrs. George Barat, or Mary Ann Barat
    - Barcigyan, G., Madame, circa 1905; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 50)
      Active in Cairo, Egypt, circa 1900-1910
    - Bardsley, Alice Wright Moss, Mrs. (born circa 1866), 1900-1909; (2 cabinet photographs) (Box 3, Folder 51)
      Active in Ashton-under-Lyne, England, 1900-1909
      Also known as Mrs. J. Bardsley or Mrs. John Bardsley
    - Barker, Julia K. Adams, Mrs. (born circa 1845), circa 1870-1883; (8 cartes-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 52)
      Active in Gardiner, Maine, circa 1870-1883
      Also known as Mrs. J. Baker or Mrs. Eugene Barker
    - Barmore, Emma C., circa 1865; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 53)
      Active in Buchanan and Niles, Michigan, circa 1865
    - Barnard, Hebe Renard Saunders, Mrs. (1820-1872), circa 1865; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 54)
      Active in London, England, 1856-1872
      Also known as Mrs. Philip Augustus Barnard
    - Barrett, Misses, circa 1865; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 55)
      Partnership of sisters Angeline Barrett (circa 1820-1888) and Emily Barrett (born circa 1822)
      Active in Lyme Regis, England, circa 1860-circa 1875
    - Barrett, C. E., Mrs. (born circa 1835), circa 1870; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 56)
      Active in Del Norte, Colorado, and Fort Dodge, Iowa, circa 1865-1879
      Also known as Mrs. G. M Barrett
    - Barton, Sarah Bushee, Mrs. (born circa 1840), circa 1870; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 57)
      Active in Beaufort, South Carolina, circa 1870
      Also known as Mrs. S. Barton
    - Bascom, R. B., Miss, circa 1886; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 58)
      Active in Prophetstown, Illinois, circa 1887
      Portrait of infant Iva Paxson (born circa 1886) of Prophetstown, Illinois, wearing a christening gown
    - Baur, Rosa, circa 1885; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 59)
      Active in Altötting, Germany, circa 1885
    - Bean, Sarah Elura Tibbetts Full, (1840-1940), circa 1885; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 60)
      Active in Mason City, Iowa, and Sioux Falls, South Dakota, circa 1880-1902
      Also known as Mrs. John Full or Mrs. Levi V. Bean
    - Bell, Jane, Mrs. (born circa 1860), circa 1890-1906; (3 cabinet photographs) (Box 3, Folder 61)
      Active in Great Torrington, England, circa 1890-1906
      Includes a portrait of a bride and groom, as well as a portrait of a dog with a young child.
    - Bellamy, Miss, circa 1890; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 62)
      Active in Indianola, Iowa, circa 1890
    - Belle-Oudry, Gertrude, Mrs. (1881-1953), circa 1904; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 63)
      Active in Berkeley, California, circa 1903-1950
      Portrait of the children of William Storm, Jr. (born circa 1877), consisting of Reynard W. Storm (born circa 1902), and Lewis A. Storm (born circa 1901)
    - Benfer, E. & E., Misses, circa 1900; (1 card photograph) (Box 3, Folder 64)
      Partnership of sisters Emma Benfer (born circa 1870) and Eva Benfer (born circa 1866)
      Active in Cambridge, Iowa, circa 1900-1904
      Portrait of Maggie O'Mara wearing a confirmation day dress
    - Bennett, Almina E., Mrs. (born circa 1834), circa 1866; (4 cartes-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 65)
      Active in Cochranton and Meadville, Pennsylvania, 1864-circa 1879
      Also known as Mrs. A. E. Bennett
    - Bergaust, Anna, circa 1905; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 66)
      Active in Larvik, Norway, circa 1905
    - Berger, Julia, Mrs. (circa 1846), circa 1892-1898; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 3, Folder 67)
      Active in Elgin, Iowa, 1892-1898
      Also known as Mrs. J. Berger
    - Berglof, H. M., Mrs., circa 1890; (2 cabinet photographs) (Box 3, Folder 68)
      Active in Concordia, Marquette, and Hutchinson, Kansas, circa 1885-circa 1905
    - Bergström, Emilie, circa 1890-1920; (11 cartes-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 69)
      Active in Avesta, Borlänge, and Hedemora, Sweden, circa 1890-1920
    - Bertolacci, Misses, circa 1870; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 3, Folder 70)